[
    {
        "question": "Ic (<em>willan</em>) #### mid flode folc acwellan ond cynna gehwilc cucra wuhta — I intend to kill with a flood the people and every kind of living thing",
        "correctAnswer": "wille",
        "explanation":"Here 'willan' is in the first person singular form 'wille' as the subject is 'ic'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hwyder (<em>willan</em>) #### ðu gangan? — Where do you intend to go?",
        "correctAnswer": "wilt",
        "explanation":"Here 'willan' is in the second person singular form 'wilt' as the subject is 'ðu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se biscop sceal þe (<em>willan</em>) #### onfon Godes mildheortnesse þrafian þa mæssepreostas mid lufe ond mid laþe þæt hie healdan Godes æwe on riht — The bishop that wants to obtain God's mercy, must compel the priests with love and with fear to correctly preserve God’s law",
        "correctAnswer": "wile",
        "explanation":"Here 'willan' is in the third person singular form 'wile' as the subject is 'se biscop'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þry dagas to lafe syndon þæt hie þe (<em>willan</em>) #### acwellan — Three days remain before the day comes on which they intend to kill you",
        "correctAnswer": "willaþ|willað",
        "explanation":"Here 'willan' is in the plural form 'willaþ' as the subject is 'hie'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Forðy ic (<em>willan</em>) #### ðætte hie ealneg æt ðære stowe wæren — Therefore I wanted them always to be there",
        "correctAnswer": "wolde",
        "explanation":"Here 'willan' is in the past first person singular form 'wolde' as the subject is 'ic'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic geanbidode swiðe wel oð ic wisse hwæt ðu (<em>willan</em>) #### and hu ðu hit understandan woldest — I waited very willingly until I knew what you wanted and how you would understand it",
        "correctAnswer": "woldest",
        "explanation":"Here 'willan' is in the past second person singular form 'wolde' as the subject is 'ðu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He cwæð ðæt he (<em>willan</em>) #### ðam wife gemyltsian — He said that he wanted to pardon the woman",
        "correctAnswer": "wolde",
        "explanation":"Here 'willan' is in the past third person singular form 'wolde' as the subject is 'he'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Loð þa eode to his twam aðumum þe (<em>willan</em>) #### wifian on his twam dohtrum — Lot then went to his two sons in law, who intended to marry his two daughters",
        "correctAnswer": "woldon",
        "explanation":"Here 'willan' is in the past plural form 'woldon' as the subject is 'his twam aðumum'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hwæt (<em>willan</em>) #### ic ðissum wiðersacan geandwyrdan? — What answer will I give to this denial?",
        "correctAnswer": "wille",
        "explanation":"Here 'willan' is in the first person singular form 'wille' as the subject is 'ic'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Cwædon him to: Gif þu ne (<em>willan</em>) #### us geðafian in swa æðelicum þinge þe we biddað ne meaht þu in usse mægðe ne ussum gemanan wunian — They said to him: 'If you will not consent to us in so noble a matter, as we ask, you may not dwell in our country nor in our society'",
        "correctAnswer": "wilt",
        "explanation":"Here 'willan' is in the second person singular form 'wilt' as the subject is 'þu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Elpendes hyd (<em>willan</em>) #### drincan wætan, gelice spynge deð — An elephant’s hide will absorb liquid, like a sponge does",
        "correctAnswer": "wile",
        "explanation":"Here 'willan' is in the third person singular form 'wile' as the subject is 'Elpendes hyd'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þonne þy ylcan dæge þe hie hine to þæm ade beran (<em>willan</em>) #### todælað hie his feoh — Then on the same day when they intended to bear him to the pyre, they divide his wealth",
        "correctAnswer": "willaþ|willað",
        "explanation":"Here 'willan' is in the plural form 'willaþ' as the subject is 'hie'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He nyste hwæt ic (<em>willan</em>) #### — He didn't know what I wanted",
        "correctAnswer": "wolde",
        "explanation":"Here 'willan' is in the past first person singular form 'wolde' as the subject is 'ic'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hwi (<em>willan</em>) #### þu beswican þæt mære wif Melantian mid forligre? — Why would you entice that excellent woman Melantian with fornication?",
        "correctAnswer": "woldest",
        "explanation":"Here 'willan' is in the past second person singular form 'woldest' as the subject is 'þu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þa Darius geseah þæt he ouerwunnen beon wolde, þa (<em>willan</em>) #### he hiene selfne on ðæm gefeohte forspillan — When Darius saw that he would be overrun, then he wanted to kill himself on the battlefield",
        "correctAnswer": "wolde",
        "explanation":"Here 'willan' is in the past third person singular form 'wolde' as the subject is 'he'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ond wið þæm þa ðe in oðre wisan don (<em>willan</em>) #### he wæs mid welme micelre ellenwodnisse onbærned — And against those who wanted to do otherwise he was inspired with great fervor and zeal",
        "correctAnswer": "woldon",
        "explanation":"Here 'willan' is in the past plural form 'woldon' as the subject is 'þa ðe'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    }
]